<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Custom Pages"
       id="custom-pages">

    <p>Although it is possible to use HTML tags in the plugin description, usually it is not enough when it comes to
        adding and editing additional content. Moreover, making changes to the Plugin page often requires publishing a
        new version of the plugin itself, while trying to include a variety of kinds of texts, like descriptions,
        manuals, promo material, and so on, can make the overall description bulky.
    </p>
    <p>To address these problems, the <control>Custom Pages</control> feature has been implemented. It allows the author
        of a plugin
        to add and manage custom content via the <path>Custom Pages</path> tab. These pages could be used for:
    </p>
    <p>
        <list>
            <li>
                Marketing landing pages
            </li>
            <li>
                Presenting additional information
            </li>
            <li>
                Plugin documentation
            </li>
            <li>
                etc.
            </li>
        </list>
    </p>

    <chapter title="Create a new Custom Page">
        <p>Custom pages can be created only for existing plugins. You cannot create custom pages if you doesn't have any
            uploaded plugins on the Marketplace. It is still possible to create custom pages even if the plugin has not
            been
            approved yet.
        </p>
        <p>To create a new custom page, open the <path>Custom Pages</path> tab on the plugin page and click the
            <path>Add New Page</path>
            button:
        </p>
        <img src="no_custom_page.png" alt="Create a new Custom Page" width="1140"/>
        <p>After that, more custom pages can be added by clicking the <path>Add New Page</path> button on the left
            panel.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Manage a Custom Page">
        <p>The following features are available for the custom pages:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <li>
                    Markdown editor
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ability to see page previews
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ability to upload images
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ability to save the page as a draft before publishing
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>
        <img src="new_custom_page.png" alt="Manage a Custom Page" width="1140"/>
        <p>A name and an address of a new page can be up to 24 symbols long. By default, the address is the same as the
            page
            name, but they can be edited separately.
        </p>
        <p>Under the name field is a Markdown editor. You can use the most common Markdown features here:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <li>
                    Headings
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        # H1
                        ## H2
                        ### H3
                        #### H4
                        ##### H5

                        Alternative H1
                        ======

                        Alternative H2
                        ------
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Bold
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        **Text in bold**
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Italics
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        *Text in italics*
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Links
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        [Link](URL)
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Citation
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        > Citation
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Code
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        `Code`
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Pictures
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        ![Picture](URL)
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Unordered list
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        * Unordered list can use asterisks
                        - Or minuses
                        + Or even pluses
                    </code>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ordered list
                    <code style="block" lang="markup">
                        1. First ordered list item
                        2. Second item
                        3. Another item
                    </code>
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>You can switch between the Markdown editor and preview at any time by clicking the <control>
            Markdown/Preview
        </control> selector
            under the custom page name field.
        </p>
        <p>Under the Markdown editor is a picture uploader and the <control>Save</control>, <control>Publish</control>/<control>
            Unpublish
        </control> and <control>Discard</control> buttons.
        </p>
        <p>Once the custom page is saved and published it will become available for the users as a new plugin tab after
            the
            <path>Reviews</path>
            tab.
        </p>
        <p>A custom page can be deleted by clicking the *Remove* button with the trash bin icon next to the custom page
            address field.
        </p>
    </chapter>

</topic>