<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Hidden Plugin Release"
       id="hidden-plugin">
<p>
    If you need to release a plugin on Marketplace silently, without making it publicly available, you can mark it as <emphasis>Hidden</emphasis>. This feature can be beneficial if you want to:
</p>
    <p>
        <list>
            <li>
                Conduct beta testing (in addition to the <a href="custom-release-channels.xml">custom release channels</a>),
            </li>
            <li>
                <a href="plugin-overview-page.xml">Set the plugin page</a>, links, media, documentation,
            </li>
            <li>
                <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/legal/approval-guidelines">Pass the approval process</a> before the planned public release,
            </li>
            <li>
                Prepare the <a href="plugin-monetization.xml">monetization</a> of your plugin beforehand.
            </li>
        </list>
    </p>

<chapter id="hide-plugin" title="How to hide a plugin" level="3">
    <p>
        To hide a plugin, you need to add Hidden flag during the <a href="uploading-a-new-plugin.xml">initial upload</a> of the plugin on JetBrains Marketplace. This flag will ensure that the plugin will not appear in the search results of the Marketplace website, IDE plugin manager, and search engines.
    </p>
    <img src="upload-new-plugin.png" alt="Upload a hidden plugin" width="490"></img>
    <warning>
        <p>
            Plugin can only be hidden on the initial upload. It is not possible to hide an existing plugin.
        </p>
    </warning>
    <p>
        Users can still access and download the plugin if provided with a direct link. The plugin can be found on your author's page, on the Organization page if the plugin is added to it, or if other plugins use it as a dependency.
    </p>
    <p>
        The lifecycle of a hidden plugin is the same as that of a usual one. Once uploaded, it is reviewed and approved by the Marketplace team. You can make your plugin a paid one, upload new updates, and manage other settings. Plugin approval or transition to a paid model won't unhide the plugin, so you can have a fully prepared plugin before the public release. You can also remove your plugin while still in a hidden state.
    </p>
</chapter>
<chapter id="unhide-plugin" title="How to unhide a plugin" level="3">
    <p>
        To unhide your plugin, you need to remove the Hidden flag from the plugin's page on the Marketplace website. After this, the plugin becomes available to the public, and users can easily find it in the plugin manager of the IDE and on the Marketplace website. It might take some time for third-party search engines to index the plugin page.
    </p>
    <warning>
        <p>
            It is important to note that unhiding a plugin cannot be reversed. Make sure your plugin is ready for public release.
        </p>
    </warning>
    <p>
        To unhide the plugin, click the <control>Publish Plugin</control> button:
    </p>
    <img src="plugin_hidden.png" alt="Hidden plugin" width="1267"></img>
    <p>
        After that, confirm the action:
    </p>
    <img src="plugin_hidden_confirm.png" alt="Confirm unhiding" width="1267"></img>
    <p>
        And then, your plugin becomes available:
    </p>
    <img src="pluign_unhidden.png" alt="Plugin released" width="1267"></img>
</chapter>
</topic>