<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Organizations"
       id="organizations">

    <p>Organizations simply let you gather all the plugins and plugin authors associated with your company on a single
        page that also provides information such as a link to your company’s website and an email address. Personal
        plugins do not belong to an organization and do not need to be transferred. We recommend creating an
        organization for companies or individual users who are planning to sell plugins or provide services such as
        bespoke plugin development, plugin training, and plugin translation.
    </p>

    <chapter title="Creating an organization">
        <p>To create an organization, navigate to your profile on JetBrains Marketplace, switch to the <emphasis>My
            Organizations
        </emphasis> tab, and click the <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/organizations/new">Add Organization</a> button:
        </p>

        <img src="AddOrganization.png" alt="Add Organization"
             width="406"/>

        <note>
            <p>Keep in mind that the user who creates an organization becomes its administrator.</p>
        </note>
        <p>Each organization has a public name and a unique ID. Be sure to choose your Organization ID carefully,
            because you won’t be able to edit this parameter later on. You should also keep in mind that one
            organization cannot have multiple Organization IDs.
        </p>

        <img src="CreateOrganization.png" alt="Create Organization"
             width="406"/>

        <p>All the other information, including the Organization Name, email address, and website, can be updated at any
            time.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Organization administrators">
        <p>As an administrator, you can:</p>
        <list>
            <li>Manage all the plugins under your organization.</li>
            <li>Update the organization details, including the banking information.</li>
            <li>Add new members to the organization.</li>
            <li>Grant additional administrator roles to other organization members.</li>
            <li>Revoke administrator privileges.</li>
            <li>
                <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/marketplace/reserved-plugin-ids.html">Reserve plugin IDs</a>
            </li>
        </list>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Adding members">
        <p>To add more members, you just need to open the <control>Edit Organization</control> page, switch to the <control>
            People &amp; Plugins
        </control> tab, and enter the plugin author's ID in the <control>Add User</control> field.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Associating plugins with an organization">
        <p>To associate plugins with an organization, the administrator or the plugin’s author should specify the
            Organization ID in the <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-configuration-file.html">
                plugin.xml
            </a> file:
        </p>

        <p>
            <control>IntelliJ IDEA-based IDEs:</control>
        </p>
        <p>
            <code style="block" lang="xml">
        <![CDATA[
                <vendor>OrganizationID</vendor>
                ]]>
    </code>
        </p>

        <p>
            <control>TeamCity:</control>
        </p>
        <p>
            <code style="block" lang="xml">
            <![CDATA[
                <vendor>
                    <name>OrganizationID</name>
                </vendor>
                ]]>
        </code>
        </p>

        <p>
            <control>Resharper:</control>
        </p>
        <p>
            <emphasis>For more details, please refer to <a
                    href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/resharper/sdk/CreateNuGetPackageForPlugin.html">this page</a>.
            </emphasis>
        </p>
        <p>
            <code style="block" lang="xml">
        <![CDATA[
                <id>OrganizationID.PluginName</id>
                ]]>
    </code>
        </p>
        <p>Once this has been done, you will have the option to transfer the plugin to the organization:</p>

        <img src="transferorg.png" alt="Add Organization" width="850"/>

        <warning>
            <p>If this button does not appear, please make sure that you specified the Organization ID correctly. Keep
                in mind that the Organization ID may differ from the Organization Name.
            </p>
        </warning>

        <p>Once the plugin has been transferred, the plugin authors will retain the right to manage their plugins, even
            if some of them do not belong to the organization. At this point, the plugin may also be managed by the
            organization's administrators.
        </p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Verifying organizations">
        <p>If an organization would like to be marked as "Verified", one of its members should contact JetBrains
            Marketplace
            support by sending an email to <a href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Submitting vendor information">
        <p>Paid and freemium plugins must belong to an organization and must be associated with the name, either the
            Company Name or the full legal name of the plugin’s author, that is used in the Sales System.
        </p>
        <p>You can submit your banking information in the Vendor Information tab:</p>

        <img src="VendorInfo.png" alt="Vendor Information tab"
             width="354"/>

        <warning>
            <p>If you don’t see this tab, please contact us at <a href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">
                marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
            </p>
        </warning>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Transferring plugins from one organization to another">
        <p>You can easily move free plugins to another organization by following these steps:</p>

        <p>
            <list type="decimal">
                <li>De-associate the plugin from its current organization by removing it in the <emphasis>Users &amp;
                    Plugins
                </emphasis> tab.
                </li>
                <li>Update the Organization ID in the plugin.xml file and upload this version to the marketplace.</li>
                <li>Transfer the plugin to the new organization on the plugin’s <emphasis>Overview</emphasis> page.
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>

        <p>For freemium or paid plugins, the procedure is not so simple, and it requires the involvement of the
            Marketplace Support team. If you wish to transfer a freemium or paid plugin, please contact us at <a
                    href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
        </p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter title="FAQ">
        <p>Q: Why should I create an Organization and transfer my plugins to it?</p>
        <p>A: Organizations increase the credibility of plugins and simplify the search process for end users, all while
            easing the plugin management process for you. Having an organization will also make it harder for anyone
            else to
            use your name or brand without your permission. Finally, if you want to sell your plugin, it must belong to
            an
            organization.
        </p>
        <p>Q: What is the difference between organization-owned plugins and personal plugins?</p>
        <p>A: There are no huge differences. Creating an organization is more like a tool for maintaining several
            plugins or
            selling them. A single (and free) personal plugin doesn’t really need to be transferred to an organization.
            Furthermore, if you’re an author who belongs to an organization, you can still keep your own plugins as
            personal
            ones.
        </p>
        <p>Q: What will happen to my plugins if I transfer them to an organization?</p>
        <p>A: Plugins that you move will have a note added to them that says they belong to the organization. They will
            also
            be listed on the organization’s page. Make sure that the value in the Vendor field is the same as the
            Organization ID. Please see the documentation for further details.
        </p>

    </chapter>

</topic>