<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Publishing and Listing your plugin"
       id="publishing-and-listing-your-plugin">

    <p>The JetBrains Marketplace plugin page is the webpage used for JetBrains Marketplace listings. It provides users with useful
        links and information about your plugin’s functionality, product compatibility, versions, and pricing (if
        applicable). When you upload a plugin to JetBrains Marketplace, it becomes available to over 10 million users of
        JetBrains products. They can download, evaluate, and buy your plugin from the plugin page, as well as rate and
        review it.
    </p>
    <p>A high-quality page is essential to attracting and engaging new customers, which will result in a higher number
        of downloads. So, it is important to prepare appropriate, high-quality content for the plugin page before
        uploading it to JetBrains Marketplace.
    </p>

    <chapter title="Plugin page review">
        <p>After uploading a plugin to JetBrains Marketplace, it will be manually reviewed by the JetBrains Marketplace team. You will be
            contacted and asked to make changes if we find anything that doesn’t fit our guidelines. To speed up the
            review
            process, make sure the information you provide is complete and correct. Note that the plugin page
            requirements
            are subject to change, as JetBrains Marketplace is constantly evolving. Be prepared to adjust to new requirements
            as
            they come out.
        </p>

        <note>
            <p>We may review published plugins at our discretion. We reserve the right to unpublish a plugin if an
                author rejects or doesn’t respond to our requests for adjustments.
            </p>
        </note>

        <p>You can find the key requirements and tips for creating a plugin page in the <a
                href="plugin-overview-page.xml">Plugin Overview
            page
        </a> section.
        </p>
    </chapter>

</topic>
