<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Special Coupons from Plugin Developers"
       id="coupon-offers">

    <p>Authors of paid plugins can create custom offers for their customers.</p>
    <procedure style="steps" title="Create a new offer">
        <step>
            Open the <path>Sales Info</path> tab of your plugin page.
        </step>
        <step>
            Click the <control>Add New Offer</control> button:
            <img src="sales_info.png" alt="Sales Info" width="2758"/>
        </step>
        <step>
            Enter a name and (optionally) a description for the new offer in the opened form.
            This form helps you generate single-use coupons for your customers.
            <img src="new_offer.png" alt="Offer Form" width="3584"/>
        </step>
        <step>
            Enter either a <control>Discount Value</control> or a <control>Free Period</control>. If you set a Free
            Period Discount, customers who apply
            this offer will be able to use your plugin for free during this period. If you set a Discount Value,
            customers can use this discount to purchase a monthly or annual subscription for your plugin (depending on
            the <control>Billing Period</control> you specify).
        </step>
        <step>
            (Optional) Specify an <control>End date</control> after which the coupons generated for this offer will
            expire. If you don’t specify a
            <control>Billing Period</control>, the offer is available for both monthly and annual subscription types.
            You can also specify the
            <control>Countries</control>
            in which you want your offer to be available.
        </step>
    </procedure>
    <p>
        After submitting this form, your new offer will appear in the <path>Current Offers</path> section of the <path>
        Sales Info
    </path> tab
        where you can edit your offers, remove them, and generate coupons.
    </p>
    <warning>
        <p>
            If you remove an offer, all coupons associated with it will be invalidated.
        </p>
    </warning>
    <procedure title="Generate coupons" style="steps">
        <step>
            Click the offer name in the <path>Current Offers</path> section on the <path>Sales Info</path> tab.
            <img src="generate_coupons.png" alt="Generate Coupons" width="2564"/>
        </step>
        <step>
            Enter the number of new coupons you want to create.
        </step>
        <step>
            Click <control>Generate New Coupons</control>.
        </step>
        <step>
            You can then copy the coupon code or download the generated coupons as PDF files to send to your users.
            <img src="download_pdf.png" alt="Coupons Form" width="1824"/>
        </step>
    </procedure>
</topic>