<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="End User License Agreement - EULA"
       id="eula">

    <p>The use of the plugin <b>will be covered by the EULA between plugin author/vendor and an end-user, there is no
        EULA
        between JetBrains and end-user on third-party plugins</b>.
    </p>

    <p>You must provide your own end user license agreement (known as <emphasis>Developer EULA</emphasis>) with any
        Plugin via
        JetBrains
        Marketplace. Developer EULA must, at a minimum, include terms consistent with, and at least as protective of
        JetBrains as the terms in the Standard EULA. The Standard EULA cannot be used instead of your Developer EULA,
        unless
        you make the necessary modifications to it to adjust it to your needs.
    </p>

    <p>The Developer EULA must specify, among other things, that you are the licensor of your Plugins and that JetBrains
        is not a party to Developer EULA.
    </p>

    <p>JetBrains will be acting as a reseller taking money for third-party plugins and will be transferring all sale
        revenue (holding JetBrains commission) to the plugin vendor.
    </p>

    <p>The current version of the Standard EULA from the <a
            href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/legal/developer-agreement">JetBrains Marketplace Developer
        Agreement</a>:
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>
            Appendix 1
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        The Standard EULA (End User License Agreement) displayed below is primarily intended as an example of a EULA to
        accompany your Plugins. It cannot be used without necessary modifications. Using your own EULA or similar
        license
        agreement granting rights to users of your Plugin is recommended. Provision of this Standard EULA does not
        constitute legal advice; advice from a qualified attorney is required. If you use the wording presented below in
        the
        Standard EULA, you acknowledge that JetBrains is not liable for its use by you in any way and that you have to
        modify it to suit your individual needs.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>
            Standard EULA
        </b>
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"Developer"</b>
        means
        <b>\[FILL IN\]</b>
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"JetBrains"</b>
        means JetBrains s.r.o. with its registered office at Na Hřebenech II 1718/10, Prague, 14000, Czech
        Republic, registered with the Commercial Register kept by the Municipal Court of Prague, Section C, file 86211,
        ID.Nr.: 265 02 275.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"JetBrains Affiliate"</b>
        means the subsidiary and/or any associated companies of JetBrains.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"JetBrains Marketplace"</b>
        means any platform operated by JetBrains or a JetBrains Affiliate on which JetBrains or
        a JetBrains Affiliate markets Plugins for JetBrains Products, including the website
        <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com">https://plugins.jetbrains.com</a>
        and/or any other website or other platform, whether
        named JetBrains Marketplace, JetBrains Plugins Repository, or otherwise.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"JetBrains Product"</b>
        means any software program or service made available by JetBrains.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"Plugin"</b>
        means the Plugin for JetBrains Product that Developer makes available under this Standard EULA.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"Plugin Information"</b>
        means the following information and materials: (a) JetBrains Marketplace Plugin title, tags
        / category, name(s) of Developer(s), product description, icon, logo or banner images, and any other information
        related to Plugins; (b) the metadata, graphics, artwork, images, trademarks, trade names, logos and other
        descriptive or identifying information and materials associated with Developer or appears in connection with
        Plugin;
        and (c) in the case of cloud hosted Plugins, an XML/JSON descriptor of Plugin.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"Plugin Users"</b>
        means users that are able to access and use Plugin concurrently.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>"You"</b>
        means an individual or an entity concluding this Standard EULA.
    </p>
    <p>
        This Standard EULA governs the terms of use of Plugin made available to You via JetBrains Marketplace. This
        Standard
        EULA is entered into between You and Developer.
    </p>
    <p>
        If Plugin is a paid Plugin, you must ensure that the maximum number of Plugin Users does not exceed the number
        of
        Plugin Users for which you have purchased Plugin.
    </p>
    <p>
        You are authorized to use Plugin in accordance with its documentation provided by Developer and for the period
        of
        time specified by Developer.
    </p>
    <p>
        You may not modify, reverse-engineer, decompile, or disassemble Plugin in whole or in part, or create any
        derivative
        works from Plugin, or sublicense any rights in Plugin, unless otherwise expressly authorized in writing by
        Developer.
    </p>
    <p>
        Plugin is protected by copyright and other intellectual property laws and treaties. Developer or its licensors
        own
        all title, copyright and other intellectual property rights in Plugin.
    </p>
    <p>
        ALL PLUGINS ARE PROVIDED TO YOU ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS WITHOUT WARRANTIES. USE OF PLUGINS IS AT
        YOUR
        OWN RISK. DEVELOPER MAKES NO WARRANTY AS TO PLUGIN'S USE OR PERFORMANCE. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY
        APPLICABLE LAW, DEVELOPER DISCLAIMS ALL OTHER WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING,
        BUT
        NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, AND
        NON-INFRINGEMENT, WITH REGARD TO PLUGINS, AND THE PROVISION OF OR FAILURE TO PROVIDE SUPPORT SERVICES. DEVELOPER
        DOES NOT WARRANT THAT PLUGINS ARE ACCURATE, RELIABLE, OR CORRECT; THAT PLUGIN MEETS YOUR REQUIREMENTS; THAT
        PLUGINS
        WILL BE AVAILABLE AT ANY PARTICULAR TIME OR LOCATION, UNINTERRUPTED, OR SECURE; THAT ANY DEFECTS OR ERRORS WILL
        BE
        CORRECTED; OR THAT PLUGINS ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS.
    </p>
    <p>
        IN NO EVENT WILL DEVELOPER BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT OR INDIRECT COSTS, LOSSES, OR DAMAGES ASSOCIATED WITH THE
        USE OF
        DEVELOPER'S PLUGINS.
    </p>
    <p>
        DEVELOPER SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY LOST PROFITS OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, HOWEVER CAUSED, AND IN NO
        EVENT
        WILL DEVELOPER'S AGGREGATE LIABILITY ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THIS AGREEMENT OR THE USE OF PLUGIN EXCEED THE
        FEES WHICH YOU PAID VIA JETBRAINS PLUGIN MARKETPLACE SERVICE FOR PLUGINS IN THE THREE-MONTH PERIOD PRECEDING THE
        CLAIM. THIS LIMITATION WILL APPLY EVEN IF DEVELOPER HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF THE LIABILITY
        EXCEEDING
        THE AMOUNT AND NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY. JETBRAINS' LIABILITY IS
        EXCLUDED IN ITS ENTIRETY AS JETBRAINS IS NOT A PARTY TO THE CONTRACTUAL RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN DEVELOPER AND
        CUSTOMER.
    </p>

</topic>
