<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Moving to the Marketplace from other licensing/billing solutions"
       id="moving-to-marketplace">

    <chapter title="When to switch to the Marketplace?">
        <p>We generally recommend switching to JetBrains Marketplace solution with the plugin version update, so that the
            following
            workflow can be followed:
        </p>
        <p>
            <list type="decimal">
                <li>
                    Users are using a legacy licensing solution (e.g., until version 1.9.1.)
                </li>
                <li>
                    Plugin developer announces that they are going to switch to another licensing solution and provides
                    migration
                    paths. Please note that there might be contractual obligations you have to follow (based on your
                    EULA or contract
                    with customers.)
                </li>
                <li>
                    Version 2.0.0. is released with JetBrains Marketplace licensing, users migrate to it over time, version
                    1.9.1, and
                    previous are still available with the old licensing solutions.
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>
            It might be technically possible to support both licensing mechanisms for some time in a single plugin, but
            it might
            complicate troubleshooting and licensing support, that's why we recommend switching to the Marketplace with
            the
            version update.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Different users migration paths">
        <p>In general, we have a rather simple migration process performed (on the technical side) via REST API or
            simple
            CSV
            upload on our side.
        </p>
        <p>The migration process is greatly complicated by the privacy protection mechanisms we have to employ to
            protect
            the
            personal information of your customers.
        </p>
        <p>You, and not JetBrains, have a right to access and process the personal data of your customers, that's why we
            can't
            simply accept a list of customers and issue the licenses to them as a part of the migration process. We need
            to
            make
            sure that the data is passed according to GDPR and other regulations covering personal data protection.
        </p>
        <p>We have come up with three ways of migration:</p>

        <chapter title="GDPR-compliant customers list passed from Plugin Developer to JetBrains">
            <p>
                <list type="decimal">
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer reaches out to the customers and obtains explicit permission to transfer their
                        personal data to
                        JetBrains as a part of the migration process.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer signs a special data-sharing agreement with JetBrains. The agreement describes
                        the process of
                        data transfer and the following processing of the personal data.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer provides a list of customers with the required data (name, email, billing
                        address, license term,
                        etc. - see below the data we require for different types of customers.)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        JetBrains will generate licenses for those customers in a new format (so that you can switch
                        them to JetBrains
                        Marketplace.)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        JetBrains will send out license keys and other information to the customers so that they switch
                        the license (as
                        soon as your plugin is sold on JetBrains Marketplace.)
                    </li>
                </list>
            </p>
        </chapter>

        <chapter title="End-user submitting the information directly to JetBrains (verified by Plugin Developer)">
            <p>
                <list type="decimal">
                    <li>
                        JetBrains publishes a special Landing Page that has a form for personal data submission
                        (everything required for
                        a license to be issued.) The form also contains a disclaimer of data shared with JetBrains (and
                        the following data
                        sharing with the plugin developer is done as of the JetBrains Marketplace Developer Agreement.)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer sends the link to the page to their customers (end-users of the plugin), asking
                        them to submit
                        the information.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        End-users submit the information at the page, and notification is sent to JetBrains and Plugin
                        Developer.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer confirms the validity of the license for the end-user submitting the form.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        JetBrains issues the license to the end-user.
                    </li>
                </list>
            </p>
        </chapter>

        <chapter title="JetBrains generates special coupon codes to be provided at the check-out by end-user (distributed by Plugin
    Developer)">
            <p>
                <list type="decimal">
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer informs JetBrains on the number of existing customers of various types
                        (personal, commercial,
                        and their validity of licenses.)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        JetBrains generates special coupon codes and passes them to the Plugin Developer.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plugin Developer distributes the coupon codes to the end-users (customers.)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Coupon codes are used by the plugin end-users (customers) to issue a license to their email.
                    </li>
                </list>
            </p>
        </chapter>

        <note>
            <p>
                Please note, that these migration workflows can be combined.
            </p>
        </note>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Required information">
        <chapter title="What information do we need to issue licenses for individual customers">
            <p>
                <list>
                    <li>
                        First Name
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Last Name
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Email
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Country
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        (optional) Phone
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Billing address
                        <list>
                            <li>
                                Address
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                City
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                ZIP Code
                            </li>
                        </list>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        License validity (date from YYYY-MM-DD ... to YYYY-MM-DD)
                    </li>
                </list>
            </p>
        </chapter>
        <chapter title="What information will we need to issue licenses for commercial customers">
            <p>
                <list>
                    <li>
                        Company Name
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        First Name
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Last Name
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Email
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Country
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        (optional) Phone
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Billing address
                        <list>
                            <li>
                                Address
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                City
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                ZIP Code
                            </li>
                        </list>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        License validity (date from YYYY-MM-DD ... to YYYY-MM-DD)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Number of licenses (for a bunch of licenses of different validity)
                    </li>
                </list>
            </p>
        </chapter>
    </chapter>
    <p>
        We won't add past orders with $$$ to our systems not to screw up the revenue statistics and commission
        calculation,
        but we can add such (or any other) information in the order/customer notes.
    </p>

</topic>
