<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Sales-related emails and in-product notifications to end users"
       id="sales-related-emails">

    <p>For plugins sold via JetBrains Marketplace, we take care of sales-related communications like order request confirmations,
        renewal reminders, invoicing, and refunds.
        The users of paid plugins on JetBrains Marketplace receive the same automated email campaigns as JetBrains product users,
        which provides a consistent experience across platforms.
    </p>
    <p>
        We send the following emails to your evaluators and customers:
    </p>
    <p>
        <list>
            <li>
                Quote request and quote expiration reminders.
            </li>
            <li>
                License certificates.
            </li>
            <li>
                License expiration messages (90, 45, and 14 days before license expiration for the Subscription Pack, as
                well as
                on the date of payment and 7 days after the subscription pack expires.
            </li>
        </list>
    </p>
    <p>The Subscription Pack serves as a way to co-term subscriptions expiring at different times to the same expiration
        date. The notification includes information about all products a user is subscribed to, including paid plugins.
    </p>
    <p>
        Here are examples of the emails we send:
    </p>
    <img src="email-example.png" alt="Example1" width="1600"/>
    <img src="email-example-2.png" alt="Example2" width="1478"/>

    <chapter title="In-product Notifications">
        <p>Users receive notifications about new plugin versions and plugin license and trial expirations right inside
            their
            IDE. These messages prompt users to update plugins to the latest version, renew subscriptions, or buy and
            activate
            licenses.
        </p>
        <img src="email-in-product-notifications.png" alt="In-product Notifications" width="844"/>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Plugin nurturing emails">
        <p>These are campaigns developed specifically for users of plugins paid via JetBrains Marketplace:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <b>Welcome email</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        This is delivered to users when they first activate a trial license of a plugin.
                        This email contains a link to your plugin page, documentation, and bug tracker (if present on
                        the plugin page).
                        Please populate the dedicated fields in the plugin page admin settings with the links to these
                        resources.
                    </p>
                    <img src="email-links.png" alt="Links" width="1600"/>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <b>
                            Trial expiration reminder
                        </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        This email is sent at the end of the trial period and directs the user to the plugin pricing
                        page.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <b>
                            Rate and review the plugin
                        </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        This email is sent to plugin users who purchased a plugin a month ago. It encourages them to
                        rate and review the
                        plugin.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Here’s how the emails look:
                    </p>
                    <img src="email-thanks.png" alt="Thank you" width="1600"/>
                    <img src="email-subscription.png" alt="Your Subscription" width="1600"/>
                    <img src="email-feedback.png" alt="Your Feedback" width="1600"/>
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="How can I contact the users of my plugin directly?">
        <p>According to the <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/legal/terms-of-use">JetBrains Marketplace
            Agreement</a>,
            JetBrains can provide you with information about your plugin customers to enable communications related to
            plugin
            support, sales-related information like pricing changes, and other necessary emails to keep customers using
            their
            plugins. JetBrains applies the data minimization principle in these handovers to make sure only relevant
            personal
            data is handed over for these purposes.
        </p>

        <warning>
            <p>Please note, that JetBrains doesn't provide you direct access to customer information unless they have
                purchased the plugin.
            </p>
        </warning>

        <p>In order to send product-related emails and marketing offers, you must explicitly get the user's consent.
            Consider
            adding a subscription form to your site, implementing an email collecting form in the product, or adding a
            link
            to
            your subscription center on the plugin page.
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>
                You should also provide a link to your privacy policy. We recommend doing so as a custom link on your
                plugin
                page.
            </b>
        </p>
        <img src="email-privacy.png" alt="Privacy Policy" width="1492"/>
    </chapter>

</topic>
