<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
        SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">
<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Release the Plugin"
       id="release-plugin">

    <note>
        <p>
            Keep in mind that you are able to perform all the tests on our <a href="marketplace-demo.xml">Demo</a> instance
            before publishing your plugin to JetBrains Marketplace.
        </p>
    </note>


    <p>Once everything is done, you are ready to start the release process.</p>
    <p>
        <list type="decimal">
            <li>
                <p>Make sure that you have an <a href="organizations.xml">Organization</a> and that you have submitted
                    your banking
                    information
                    under the <path>Vendor Information</path> tab.
                </p>

                <img src="test_org.png" alt="My Organizations tab" width="1500"/>
                <img src="VendorInfo.png" alt="Vendor Information tab" width="1522"/>


                <tip>
                    <p>If you don’t see the tab for banking information, contact our Support Team <a
                            href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
                    </p>
                </tip>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>If this is your initial release, upload the plugin to <a
                        href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/">JetBrains
                    Marketplace</a>.
                </p>
                <img src="plugin_upload.png" alt="A button for plugin upload" width="1122"/>
                <p>If you are switching the model from being a free plugin to paid/freemium,  <a
                        href="plugin-updates.xml">upload an
                    update</a>.
                </p>
                <warning>
                    <p>
                        Make sure that your plugin meets all the  <a
                            href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/legal/approval-guidelines">requirements
                    </a> and that you’ve correctly specified the <a href="versioning-of-paid-plugins.xml">plugin version
                        and release
                        date</a>.
                    </p>
                </warning>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>If you have not already done so, transfer the plugin to your Organization by going to the plugin
                    overview
                    page and clicking the <control>Transfer to Organization</control> button:
                </p>
                <img src="transfer-button.png" alt="Add to Organization" width="1884"/>
                <tip>
                    <p>
                        If this button is not available, make sure that you specified the <a href="organizations.xml">
                        Organization ID
                    </a> correctly. Keep in mind that your Organization ID may differ from your Organization Name.
                    </p>
                </tip>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>Go to the <path>Sales Info</path> tab on the Plugin page and press the <control>Add to Marketplace
                </control> button to fill in the sales
                    details.
                </p>
                <img src="add-to-market.png" alt="Add to Marketplace" width="1306"/>
                <tip>
                    <p>
                        If you don’t see this button, please make sure you specified your banking information under the  <path>
                        Vendor Information
                    </path> tab for your <a href="organizations.xml">Organization</a>.
                    </p>
                </tip>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>Be careful when filling out this form. We recommend checking out our <a
                        href="pricing-guidelines.xml">Pricing
                    Guidelines
                </a> and details on the supported <a href="license-types-and-schemes.xml">Licensing Schemes</a>.
                </p>

                <img src="sales_details.png" alt="Fill in the sales info"
                     width="354"/>
                <tip>
                    <p>Add an annual billing period if you're planning to support free community programs.</p>
                </tip>

                <p>If some fields need to be changed after submission, write to the Marketplace Team at
                    <a href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>Below the sales details, you can select any
                    <a href="community-programs.xml">community discounts</a>
                    you want your plugin to offer.
                </p>

                <img src="community_prog.png" alt="Select Community Programs" width="1938"/>

                <p>Keep in mind that free community programs require an annual billing period. To enable it,
                    contact our Support Team at <a href="mailto:marketplace@jetbrains.com">marketplace@jetbrains.com</a>.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Once these steps have been performed, we will review your plugin within two business days. You will
                    receive a
                    notification as soon as the status of the review changes or if there are any questions regarding the
                    approval of
                    your plugin.
                </p>
            </li>
        </list>
    </p>

</topic>